<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Rosalyn Spencer</title>
    <link>http://localhost:53445/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Rosalyn Spencer</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Rosalyn Spencer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="http://localhost:53445/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Schooling Research Findings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:53445/project/home-schooling-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:53445/project/home-schooling-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This research paper explores the practice, challenges, and outcomes of home education, drawing on my personal experience of home educating my own two children along with broader research in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings discuss various approaches to home education, the motivations behind families choosing this path, and the educational and social outcomes observed in home-educated children. The paper examines how home education can be tailored to individual learning styles and needs, offering insights into successful methodologies and potential challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research also considers how home education interacts with mainstream educational systems and societal expectations, providing a nuanced view of this alternative educational approach.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Schools - Two Case Studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:53445/project/small-schools-case-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:53445/project/small-schools-case-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This detailed case study examines two small schools, providing an in-depth look at their educational philosophies, teaching approaches, organizational structures, and community impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing from my extensive research during my journey visiting fifteen small schools affiliated with Human Scale Education, these case studies highlight the distinctive characteristics that make small schools effective learning environments. The paper discusses how these schools address the individual needs of their students, create supportive community atmospheres, and navigate the challenges of operating outside mainstream educational systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research compares different models of small school education while identifying common factors that contribute to their success. It also considers the implications for broader educational policy and practice, suggesting how elements from small schools might inform improvements in mainstream education.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
