<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Small Schools on Rosalyn Spencer</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/small-schools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Small Schools on Rosalyn Spencer</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Rosalyn Spencer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/small-schools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Started a Small School</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/small-school-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/small-school-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why I Started a Small School&amp;rdquo; tells the story of my journey in setting up and running a non-fee paying &amp;lsquo;alternative&amp;rsquo; small school. This book draws from my extensive experience of over 25 years in teaching, working with children from various backgrounds and educational needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book explores the challenges and rewards of creating an educational environment that focuses on the individual needs of children, particularly those who have struggled in mainstream education. It shares insights from my experience visiting fifteen small schools affiliated with Human Scale Education during a ten-week caravan journey through England and Scotland with my two children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This journey was not only pivotal in kick-starting my writing career but also formed the basis for my Masters Degree in Education by Research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Started a Small School</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/small-school-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/small-school-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why I Started a Small School&amp;rdquo; is the culmination of my life&amp;rsquo;s work in education, sharing the story of how I created an educational environment focused on individual needs. The book offers insights into alternative approaches to education, especially for children who have not thrived in conventional school settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The narrative draws from my diverse experiences including working with struggling students, teenagers in care, running a children&amp;rsquo;s nursery, home educating my own children, and ultimately establishing a small school. It chronicles the challenges, rewards, and lessons learned throughout this journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book reflects my belief in the importance of educational environments that recognize and nurture each child&amp;rsquo;s unique potential, providing a practical perspective on how small-scale, personalized education can make a profound difference in children&amp;rsquo;s lives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Is Beautiful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/small-is-beautiful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/small-is-beautiful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Small Is Beautiful&amp;rdquo; explores the philosophy and practical benefits of small-scale educational environments. Based on my experience in both mainstream education and running a small school, this article discusses how smaller educational settings can provide more personalized attention and better meet the individual needs of students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article draws upon my research from visiting fifteen small schools across England and Scotland, highlighting successful approaches and methodologies that foster student engagement, well-being, and academic success in these environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Schools - Two Case Studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/small-schools-case-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/small-schools-case-studies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This detailed case study examines two small schools, providing an in-depth look at their educational philosophies, teaching approaches, organizational structures, and community impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing from my extensive research during my journey visiting fifteen small schools affiliated with Human Scale Education, these case studies highlight the distinctive characteristics that make small schools effective learning environments. The paper discusses how these schools address the individual needs of their students, create supportive community atmospheres, and navigate the challenges of operating outside mainstream educational systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research compares different models of small school education while identifying common factors that contribute to their success. It also considers the implications for broader educational policy and practice, suggesting how elements from small schools might inform improvements in mainstream education.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Calm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/keeping-calm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/keeping-calm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Nursery World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Dharma School in Brighton is the first primary school in the UK to be based on Buddhist principles.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the unique educational approach of the Dharma School in Brighton, examining how Buddhist principles are integrated into its educational philosophy and daily practices. It discusses the school&amp;rsquo;s focus on mindfulness, compassion, and holistic development, offering insights into how these principles shape the learning environment and student experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from a Small World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/lessons-small-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/lessons-small-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Yorkshire Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;None of the schools I visited received government funding. And although some do charge fees, they are making no profits. Two of them have already been forced to close and for others, funding is a constant struggle.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the financial challenges faced by small, independent schools based on Rosalyn&amp;rsquo;s research trip visiting fifteen such schools across England and Scotland. It highlights the dedication of these educational institutions that operate without government funding, and the ongoing financial struggles they face despite their important contributions to education.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Started my Own School</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/why-started-own-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/why-started-own-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Natural Parent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A local benefactor had heard of our plight to find more suitable premises and had made a successful bid to buy a recently disused local village school from the local authority for our use.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article shares Rosalyn&amp;rsquo;s personal story of establishing her own small school, recounting the challenges and ultimately the fortuitous circumstances that enabled her to secure a location for the school. It highlights the community support that made the project possible, particularly focusing on the role of a local benefactor in acquiring a recently closed village school building.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
