<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nursery-World on Rosalyn Spencer</title>
    <link>http://localhost:54094/tags/nursery-world/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nursery-World on Rosalyn Spencer</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Rosalyn Spencer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="http://localhost:54094/tags/nursery-world/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Earth Matters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/earth-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/earth-matters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Nursery World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The case for an environmentally aware form of education for children in the face of climate change.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the importance of incorporating environmental awareness into early childhood education, especially considering the growing concerns about climate change. It examines how educators can introduce young children to environmental concepts in age-appropriate ways while fostering a sense of connection and responsibility towards the natural world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Special</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/feeling-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/feeling-special/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Nursery World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nurture Groups are based within mainstream settings and care for up to 12 children aged four to seven who have emotional and behavioural problems.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the concept and implementation of Nurture Groups in educational settings. These specialized groups provide targeted support for young children experiencing emotional and behavioral challenges, offering them a more structured and nurturing environment within mainstream educational settings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class of their Own</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/class-of-their-own/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/class-of-their-own/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Nursery World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A growing number of families are choosing to educate their children at home, for a variety of reasons.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article examines the increasing trend of home education in the UK, exploring the diverse motivations that lead families to choose this educational path. Drawing on her personal experience of home educating her own two children, Rosalyn provides insights into the benefits, challenges, and approaches to successful home education.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Calm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/keeping-calm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/keeping-calm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Nursery World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Dharma School in Brighton is the first primary school in the UK to be based on Buddhist principles.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the unique educational approach of the Dharma School in Brighton, examining how Buddhist principles are integrated into its educational philosophy and daily practices. It discusses the school&amp;rsquo;s focus on mindfulness, compassion, and holistic development, offering insights into how these principles shape the learning environment and student experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
