<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Education on Rosalyn Spencer</title>
    <link>http://localhost:54094/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Education on Rosalyn Spencer</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year} Rosalyn Spencer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="http://localhost:54094/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Started a Small School</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/small-school-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/small-school-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why I Started a Small School&amp;rdquo; tells the story of my journey in setting up and running a non-fee paying &amp;lsquo;alternative&amp;rsquo; small school. This book draws from my extensive experience of over 25 years in teaching, working with children from various backgrounds and educational needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book explores the challenges and rewards of creating an educational environment that focuses on the individual needs of children, particularly those who have struggled in mainstream education. It shares insights from my experience visiting fifteen small schools affiliated with Human Scale Education during a ten-week caravan journey through England and Scotland with my two children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This journey was not only pivotal in kick-starting my writing career but also formed the basis for my Masters Degree in Education by Research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earth Matters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/earth-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/earth-matters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Nursery World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The case for an environmentally aware form of education for children in the face of climate change.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the importance of incorporating environmental awareness into early childhood education, especially considering the growing concerns about climate change. It examines how educators can introduce young children to environmental concepts in age-appropriate ways while fostering a sense of connection and responsibility towards the natural world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Is Beautiful</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/small-is-beautiful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/small-is-beautiful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Small Is Beautiful&amp;rdquo; explores the philosophy and practical benefits of small-scale educational environments. Based on my experience in both mainstream education and running a small school, this article discusses how smaller educational settings can provide more personalized attention and better meet the individual needs of students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article draws upon my research from visiting fifteen small schools across England and Scotland, highlighting successful approaches and methodologies that foster student engagement, well-being, and academic success in these environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Special</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/feeling-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/feeling-special/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Nursery World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nurture Groups are based within mainstream settings and care for up to 12 children aged four to seven who have emotional and behavioural problems.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the concept and implementation of Nurture Groups in educational settings. These specialized groups provide targeted support for young children experiencing emotional and behavioral challenges, offering them a more structured and nurturing environment within mainstream educational settings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Schooling Research Findings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/home-schooling-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/home-schooling-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Featured in a Japanese TV Programme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Addressing the criticism that home educated children will grow up resentful at having been isolated from school going peers, Ray found that 95% of the homeschooled adults were pleased to have been home educated, adding that their education had not hindered them in terms of either career or education.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research discusses findings about outcomes for home-educated children, specifically addressing common concerns about socialization and future prospects. Referencing studies by Dr. Ray, it highlights that the vast majority of adults who were home educated expressed satisfaction with their educational experience and did not feel disadvantaged in their careers or further education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research paper explores the practice, challenges, and outcomes of home education, drawing on my personal experience of home educating my own two children along with broader research in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The findings discuss various approaches to home education, the motivations behind families choosing this path, and the educational and social outcomes observed in home-educated children. The paper examines how home education can be tailored to individual learning styles and needs, offering insights into successful methodologies and potential challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research also considers how home education interacts with mainstream educational systems and societal expectations, providing a nuanced view of this alternative educational approach.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class of their Own</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/class-of-their-own/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/class-of-their-own/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Nursery World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A growing number of families are choosing to educate their children at home, for a variety of reasons.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article examines the increasing trend of home education in the UK, exploring the diverse motivations that lead families to choose this educational path. Drawing on her personal experience of home educating her own two children, Rosalyn provides insights into the benefits, challenges, and approaches to successful home education.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Trip to Denmark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/trip-to-denmark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/trip-to-denmark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Human Scale Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;One of the greatest differences between English and Danish schooling is that of mutual trust and respect between pupils and teachers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article shares insights from Rosalyn&amp;rsquo;s educational research trip to Denmark, highlighting the distinctive features of the Danish education system. It particularly focuses on the foundation of mutual trust and respect that characterizes the relationship between students and teachers in Danish schools, contrasting this with educational approaches in England.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Calm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/keeping-calm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/keeping-calm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Nursery World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Dharma School in Brighton is the first primary school in the UK to be based on Buddhist principles.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the unique educational approach of the Dharma School in Brighton, examining how Buddhist principles are integrated into its educational philosophy and daily practices. It discusses the school&amp;rsquo;s focus on mindfulness, compassion, and holistic development, offering insights into how these principles shape the learning environment and student experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from a Small World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/lessons-small-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/lessons-small-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Yorkshire Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;None of the schools I visited received government funding. And although some do charge fees, they are making no profits. Two of them have already been forced to close and for others, funding is a constant struggle.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article discusses the financial challenges faced by small, independent schools based on Rosalyn&amp;rsquo;s research trip visiting fifteen such schools across England and Scotland. It highlights the dedication of these educational institutions that operate without government funding, and the ongoing financial struggles they face despite their important contributions to education.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Started my Own School</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54094/project/why-started-own-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:54094/project/why-started-own-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Published in Natural Parent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A local benefactor had heard of our plight to find more suitable premises and had made a successful bid to buy a recently disused local village school from the local authority for our use.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article shares Rosalyn&amp;rsquo;s personal story of establishing her own small school, recounting the challenges and ultimately the fortuitous circumstances that enabled her to secure a location for the school. It highlights the community support that made the project possible, particularly focusing on the role of a local benefactor in acquiring a recently closed village school building.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
